Guide to the Margaret Brown Dutch Houses Photograph Collection [1920-1936] PR 118
@ 2011 New-York Historical Society
Margaret Brown Dutch Houses Photograph Collection
[1920-1936]
PR 118
@ 2011 New-York Historical Society
3.78 Linear feet (9 boxes)
This collection consists of negatives and copy photographs of Dutch houses throughout New Jersey and New York states taken by Margaret Brown for two books commissioned by the Holland Society of New York: Dutch Houses in the Hudson Valley Before 1776 (1929) by Helen Wilkinson Reynolds, and Pre-Revolutionary Dutch Houses and Families in Northern New Jersey and Southern New York (1936) by Rosalie Fellows Bailey.
3.78 linear feet, 9 boxes
Brown, Margaret De Motte.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers.
Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to thirty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. See guidelines in Print Room for details.
Biographical Note
Margaret De Motte Brown was a photographer best known for her documentation of historic Dutch houses in New Jersey and New York states. Her pictorial depictions of these historic structures form an integral part of the books Dutch Houses in the Hudson Valley Before 1776 (1929), by her friend Helen Wilkinson Reynolds; and Pre-Revolutionary Dutch Houses and Families in Northern New Jersey and Southern New York (1936) by Rosalie Fellows Bailey. Her work was commissioned by the Holland Society, which also commissioned the studies and eventual books by Reynolds and Bailey.
Margaret Brown frequently took photographs of Vassar College events, and a number of her pictures of the school, as well as nearby Dutchess County and sites, were published in The New York Times from the 1920s through 1940s. Brown exhibited her work both domestically and abroad from the 1910s through the 1930s.
Scope and Content Note
The Margaret Brown Dutch Houses Photograph Collection spans the period from ca. 1920 to ca. 1936 and primarily contains photographs documenting houses built by Dutch immigrants during the eighteenth century in New Jersey and New York. The collection is divided into three series based on the books in which the images appeared: Dutch Houses in the Hudson Valley Before 1776; Pre-Revolutionary Dutch Houses and Families in Northern New Jersey and Southern New York; and Unidentified.
Arrangement
Photographs are arranged into the following series based on book projects:
Series I: Dutch Houses in the Hudson Valley Before 1776
Series II: Pre-Revolutionary Dutch Houses
Series III: Unidentified
Related Material at the New-York Historical Society
The book Dutch Houses in the Hudson Valley Before 1776 by Helen Wilkinson Reynolds (New York, Payson and Clarke, 1929; reprinted New York: Dover Publications, 1965) and its companion volume, Pre-Revolutionary Dutch Houses and Families in Northern New Jersey and Southern New York by Rosalie Fellows Bailey (New York: W. Morrow & Company, 1936; reprinted New York: Dover Publications, 1968) are available in the New-York Historical Society Library.
Bailey, Rosalie Fellows, 1908- Pre-Revolutionary Dutch houses and families in northern New Jersey and southern New York.; Reynolds, Helen Wilkinson. Dutch houses in the Hudson Valley before 1776.; Architecture, Colonial.; Architecture, Domestic -- New York (State).; Architecture, Domestic. -- New Jersey.; Glass negatives.; Historic buildings -- New Jersey.; Historic buildings -- New York (State).; Negatives.; Photographic prints.
- Series I: Dutch Houses in the Hudson Valley Before 1776
  Scope and Contents note
  Series I consists of original film and glass negatives and copy photographs of Dutch houses taken during the 1920s to serve as illustrations for Helen Wilkinson Reynolds' landmark book Dutch Houses in the Hudson Valley Before 1776 (1929). Negatives and copy prints are filed together, and are arranged according to the book's plate numbers (ie. R-7 corresponds to Reynolds plate number 7). Copy photographs exist for about three quarters of the negatives; every image has a negative, with a few exceptions which are noted in this finding aid. Alternative views that were not published in the book are included in this collection and are filed under the published image's plate number.
  The first seventeen plates are views of locations throughout the Hudson Valley which provide examples of typical structures and landscapes. Thereafter, plates are arranged by New York State county in the following order: Albany, Ulster, Westchester, and Dutchess Counties. Thereunder, photographs are filed by the name of the original owner. Researchers should note that the Albany County category includes several counties which fell within its original boundaries; these include Columbia, Rensselaer, Greene and Schenectady Counties. Occasionally other county designations used in the book do not reflect modern geographic boundaries; titles are annotated in parentheses with the present county if it differs from the original.
  The few photographs that were not published in the book in any form or variation are filed at the beginning of the appropriate county. Address and family names reflect those published in the book. Some of the buildings and addresses no longer exist.
  - Hudson Valley, NY
    - Introductory page, unnumbered, De Lange Rak - Hudson River, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - R-2, Kinderhook Creek, typical meadow, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - R-3, Bonte Koe (Spotted Cow), typical flat, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - R-5, Dutchess County, Poughkeepsie - Van Kleeck house, typical arch support (detail), [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 4-6)
    - R-6, Dutchess County, Poughkeepsie - Baltus Borents Van Kleeck house, typical lintel stone, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - R-7, Dutchess County, Poughkeepsie - Pieter Viele house, typical cornerstone (detail), [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - R-8, Dutchess County - Jacobus Swartwout house, typical frame construction, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
    - R-9, Dutchess County, East Fishkill - Verplanck-Van Wyck house, typical barn, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 11-13)
    - R-10, Dutchess County, Fishkill, Vis Kil - Rombout Patent, typical farmland, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - R-11, Dutchess County, Between Brinckerhoffville and Swartwoutville, typical road, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 15-17)
  - Albany County, NY
    - R-15, East Greenbush (Rensselaer County) - Hendrick Bries house, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - R-17, West Coxsackie (Greene County) - Leendert Bronck house, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 19-21)
    - R-18, Coeymans - Ariaantje Coeymans house, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 22-23)
    - R-19, Coeymans - Coeymans-Bronck house, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 24-27)
    - R-20, Claverack (Columbia County) - Conyn-Van Rensselaer house, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 28)
      General note
      [no negative]
    - R-21, near Greenen Bosch (Rensselaer County) - Hendrick Cuyler house, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 29-31)
    - R-22, Wolven Hoeck (Rensselaer County) - Petrus Douw house, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 32-33)
    - R-23, Scotia (Schenectady County) - Glen-Sanders house, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 34-35)
    - R-25, Claverack (Columbia County) - Hoogeboom house, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 36-38)
    - R-28, Claverack (Columbia County) - Cornelius C. Muller house, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 39-40)
    - R29, Bethleham - Rensselaer Nicoll house, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 41-42)
    - R30, Leeds (Greene County) - Francis Salisbury house, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 43-45)
    - R-37, Staats' Island (Rensselaer County) - Gerret Staats house, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 46-47)
    - R-38, Roeloff Jansen's Kil, (Columbia County) - Dirck Wesselse Ten Broeck house, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 48-51)
    - R-41, Kinderhook (Columbia County) - Van Alen house, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 52-54)
    - R-43, Leeds (Greene County) - Van Bergen/Vedder house, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 55-56)
    - R-44, Bethlehem - Gerret Vandenbergh house, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 57-59)
    - R-46, Athens (Greene County) - Van Loon house, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 60-61)
    - R-48, Claverack (Columbia County) - Van Rensselaer house, called Klaver Rak, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 62-63)
    - R-50, Albany - Philip Van Rensselaer house, called Cherry Hill, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 64-66)
    - R-51, Kinderhook (Columbia County) - Cornelis Van Schaack house, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - R-53, Catskill (Greene County) - Van Vechten house, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 68-69)
    - R-54, Bethlehem - Hendrick Van Wie house, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 70-71)
  - Ulster County, NY
    - No plate, unidentified, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - No plate, R - page 186, Saugerties - Brink house, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 73-74)
    - No plate, Hurley, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 75-76)
    - No plate, New Paltz - Hasbrouck-Freer house, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 77-78)
    - R-58, New Paltz - Bevier-Elting house, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 79-81)
    - R-59, Napanoch - Coenradt Bevier house, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 82-86)
    - R-60, Saugerties - Cornelis Lamberts Brink house, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 87-89)
    - R-62, Wawarsing - Jacobus Bruyn house, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 90-91)
    - R-63, Kingston - Jacobus S. Bruyn house, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 92-93)
    - R-64, Wallkill - Bruyn house, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 94-95)
    - R-65 and R-66, Shawangunk - Decker house, [1920-1929] (Box 1, Folder 96-100)
    - R-71, Marbletown - Andries De Witt house, [1920-1929] (Box 2, Folder 110-116)
    - R-72, New Paltz - Deyo house, [1920-1929] (Box 2, Folder 117)
      [2 glass plate negatives]
    - R-73, Saugerties - Du Bois-Kierstede house, [1920-1929] (Box 2, Folder 118-119)
    - R-74, Wawarsing - Johannes G. Hardenbergh house, [1920-1929] (Box 2, Folder 120-122)
    - R-75, New Paltz - Jean Hasbrouck house, [1920-1929] (Box 2, Folder 123-126)
    - R-76, Newburgh (Orange County) - Jonathan Hasbrouck house, [1920-1929] (Box 2, Folder 127-133)
    - R-77, Shawangunk - Thomas Jansen house, [1920-1929] (Box 2, Folder 134-137)
    - R-78, Rochester - Krom house, [1920-1929] (Box 2, Folder 138-139)
    - R-81, Ulster - Osterhoudt house, [1920-1929] (Box 2, Folder 140-142)
    - R-82, Marbletown - Pawling house, [1920-1929] (Box 2, Folder 143-146)
    - R-84, Saugerties - Schoonmaker house, [1920-1929] (Box 2, Folder 147)
    - R-86, Stone Ridge - The Tack Inn, [1920-1929] (Box 2, Folder 148)
    - R-89, Ulster - Benjamin Ten Broeck house, [1920-1929] (Box 2, Folder 149-150)
    - R-90, Hurley - Matthew Ten Eyck house, [1920-1929] (Box 2, Folder 151-152)
    - R-91, Gardiner - Evert Terwilliger house, [1920-1929] (Box 2, Folder 153-156)
    - R-92, High Falls - Unidentified house, 1752, [1920-1929] (Box 2, Folder 157-159)
    - R-93, Marbletown - Unidentified house, called Feather Farm, [1920-1929] (Box 2, Folder 160)
    - R-94, Kripplebush - Unidentified house, 1772, [1920-1929] (Box 2, Folder 161)
    - R-95, Rochester - Unidentified house, [1920-1929] (Box 2, Folder 162-164)
    - R-96, Esopus - Van Aken house, [1920-1929] (Box 2, Folder 165)
    - R-97, Kingston - Van Buren house, [1920-1929] (Box 2, Folder 166-167)
    - R-98, Hurley - Van Duesen house, [1920-1929] (Box 2, Folder 168-170)
    - R-99, Kingston - Van Keuren house, [1920-1929] (Box 2, Folder 171-172)
    - R-100, Rosendale - Jacob Aertsen Van Wagenen house, [1920-1929] (Box 2, Folder 173-176)
    - R-102, Rochester - Westbrook house, [1920-1929] (Box 2, Folder 177-178)
    - R-103, Hurley - Wynkoop Farm, [1920-1929] (Box 2, Folder 179)
    - R-104, Stone Ridge - Wynkoop-Lounsbery house, [1920-1929] (Box 2, Folder 180-186)
    - R-105, Saugerties - Wynkoop-Schoonmaker house, [1920-1929] (Box 2, Folder 187-188)
  - Westchester County, NY
    - R-106, Sleepy Hollow - Dutch Church, Philipse Manor, [1920-1929] (Box 2, Folder 189-193)
    - R-107, Irvington - Dutch farmhouse, Philipse Manor, [1920-1929] (Box 3, Folder 194-196)
    - R-108, Yonkers - Philipse Manor-house, [1920-1929] (Box 3, Folder 197-210)
    - R-109, Croton-on-Hudson - Van Cortlandt Manor-house and farmhouse, [1920-1929] (Box 3, Folder 211-216)
    - R-110, Van Cortlandt Park (Bronx) - Frederick Van Cortlandt house and Varian house, [1920-1929] (Box 3, Folder 217-222)
  - Dutchess County, NY
    - No plate, Van Stenburgh house, [1920-1929] (Box 3, Folder 223)
    - No plate, R-pg. 368, Manchester Bridge - Moses De Graeff house, [1920-1929] (Box 3, Folder 224-225)
    - R-111, Beacon - Madam Brett house, [1920-1929] (Box 3, Folder 226)
    - R-112, Wappingers Falls - Brewer-Mesier house, [1920-1929] (Box 3, Folder 227-230)
    - R-113, Fishkill - Derick Brinckerhoff house, [1920-1929] (Box 3, Folder 231)
    - R-114, Fishkill - John Brinckerhoff house, [1920-1929] (Box 3, Folder 232-233)
    - R-115, Fishkill - Abraham De Peyster house, [1920-1929] (Box 3, Folder 234-241)
    - R-116, Clinton - John De Witt house, [1920-1929] (Box 3, Folder 242-243)
    - R-117, Wappinger - Farmers' Landing house, [1920-1929] (Box 3, Folder 244-245)
    - R-119, Poughkeepsie - John Frear house, [1920-1929] (Box 3, Folder 246-247)
    - R-120, Clinton - Garrison Farm house, [1920-1929] (Box 3, Folder 248)
    - R-121, East Fishkill - Benjamin Hasbrouck house, [1920-1929] (Box 3, Folder 249)
    - R-122, Washington - David Johnstone house, called Lithgow, [1920-1929] (Box 3, Folder 250-251)
    - R-124, King's Highway, [1920-1929] (Box 3, Folder 252-253)
    - R-125 and R-126, Kipsbergen, [1920-1929] (Box 3, Folder 254-256)
    - R-127, Fishkill - Hendrick Kip house, [1920-1929] (Box 3, Folder 257-259)
    - R-130, New Hackensack - Old Hundred, [1920-1929] (Box 3, Folder 260-262)
    - R-131, Poughkeepsie - Palen-Platt house, [1920-1929] (Box 3, Folder 263)
    - R-132, Hyde Park - John Pawling house, [1920-1929] (Box 3, Folder 264-266)
    - R-133, Fishkill - Zebulon Southard house, [1920-1929] (Box 3, Folder 267-269)
    - R-134, East Fishkill - John Storm house, [1920-1929] (Box 3, Folder 270-272)
    - R-136, Hyde Park - William Stoutenburgh house, [1920-1929] (Box 3, Folder 273-275)
    - R-137, Hyde Park-on-Hudson - Bergh or Stoutenburgh house, [1920-1929] (Box 3, Folder 276-277)
    - R-139, Clinton - John Teller house, [1920-1929] (Box 3, Folder 278-279)
    - R-141, Poughkeepsie - Matthew Van Keuren house, [1920-1929] (Box 3, Folder 280-281)
    - R-142, Poughkeepsie - Baltus Barents Van Kleeck house, [1920-1929] (Box 3, Folder 282)
    - R-145, Pleasant Valley - Evert Van Wagenen house, [1920-1929] (Box 3, Folder 283-284)
    - R-146, Fishkill - Cornelius Van Wyck house, [1920-1929] (Box 3, Folder 285)
      [No negative]
    - R-147, East Fishkill - Cornelius R. Van Wyck house, [1920-1929] (Box 3, Folder 286-287)
    - R-148, Fishkill - Gulian Verplanck house, called Mount Gulian, [1920-1929] (Box 3, Folder 288-290)
- Series II: Pre-Revolutionary Dutch Houses and Families in Northern New Jersey and Southern New York
  Series II consists of negatives and copy print photographs of Dutch houses located in New Jersey and southern New York taken by Margaret Brown for use in Rosalie Fellows Bailey's 1936 book of the same title, which continued Reynold's work. The negatives date from the late 1920s through 1936. The order of arrangement corresponds to the order of plates in the book; plate numbers have been listed at the beginning of each description. Variations of images in the book are filed with the appropriate plate number. The arrangement begins with a few photographs which correspond to the introduction to the book, then follow in geographic order under three categories: New York, Northern New Jersey, and Southern New Jersey. Thereunder photographs are arranged alphabetically by county and then the original owner's name. As in Series I, photographs that are variations of those published in the book are filed under the appropriate plate number; photographs with no corresponding plates are filed at the beginning of each county division.
  - Pre-Revolutionary Dutch Houses (Overview)
    - B-2, Franklin Township, Somerset County, NJ - Van Wickle-Suydam house (interior), [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 291-293)
    - B-3 and B-4, Saddle River, Bergen County, NJ - Abram Ackerman house (interior), [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 294-298)
    - B-5, Closter, Bergen County, NJ - Barent and John Nagel house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 299-302)
  - New York -- Kings County
    - No plate - unidentified, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 303-305)
    - No plate - Dyckman house (New York County), [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 306-307)
    - No plate - Rycker house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 308-309)
    - No plate - Ryder house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 310-315)
    - No plate - Stillwell-Lake house(?), [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 316-322)
    - No plate, Woodard, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 323-324)
    - No plate - Wyckoff house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 325-328)
    - No plate, Bay Road - Bennett house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 329-330)
    - No plate, Bay Road and 11th Street - Bennett house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 331-332)
    - No plate, East 34th Street - Coe house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 333-334)
    - No plate, 1669 East 22nd Street - Wyckoff-Bennett house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 335-336)
    - B-7, Highland Park, Jamaica Avenue, East New York - Cornell Schenck house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 337-339)
    - B-8, 1410 Flushing Avenue, Bushwick - John Covert house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 340)
    - B-9, Gravesend Neck Road, Gravesend - Lady Moody house (?), Van Siclen house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 341)
    - B-10, Prospect Park, Flatbush Avenue, Flatbush - Pieter Lefferts house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 342)
    - B-11, 1940 East 36th Street, Flatlands - Johannes Lott house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 343-345)
    - B-12, 21 Church Avenue, Flatbush - Adrian Martense house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 346)
    - B-13, East 63rd Street near Mill Avenue, Flatlands - Jan Martense Schenck house on Mill Island, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 347)
    - B-14, Canarsie - Nicholas Schenck house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 348)
    - B-15, East 53rd Street north of Avenue N, Flatlands - Schenck-Williamson house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 349)
    - B-16, 1325 Flushing Avenue, Bushwick - Schenk-Wyckoff house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 350-354)
    - B-17, East 72nd Street, Bergen Beach, Flatlands - Stoothoff-Bergen house on Bergen Island, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 355-356)
    - B-18, 1640 48th Street, Flatlands - Stoothoff-Baxter-Kouwenhoven house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 357-359)
    - B-19, Church Avenue and East 53rd Street, Flatbush - Stryker-Schenck house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 360-363)
    - B-20, 1752 84th Street, New Utrecht - Jacob Swaert house; the Van Brunt homestead, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 364-365)
    - B-21, park at 18th Avenue and 82nd Street, New Utrecht - Jan Van Cleef house (?); Van Pelt homestead, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 366)
    - B-22, 1416 Flushing Avenue, Bushwick - Paulus Van Enden house, later Beegel's and Onderdonk's, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 367)
    - B-23, Canarsie Lane near Ralph Avenue, Flatlands Wyckoff homestead, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 368-370)
  - New York - Queens County
    - No plate, Flushing - Bowne house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 371-372)
    - B-24, Bowery Bay Road, North Beach - Abraham Lent house, later Rapalye's, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 373)
    - B-25, Bowery Bay Road, North Beach - Luyster-Kouwenhoven house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 374)
  - New York - Richmond County
    - No plate, [-]obson-Clausen house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 375-376)
    - No plate, Cortelyou house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 377-378)
    - No plate number, B-pg. 115 - Cruser-Winant-Pero house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 379-381)
    - No plate, Egbert house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 382)
    - No plate, Pratt-Decker house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 383)
    - No plate, Van Pelt-Beck house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 384-387)
    - B-26, New Dorp Lane, New Dorp - Nathaniel Britton house, later Walton's and Cubberly's, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 388)
    - B-27, 40 Wachogue Road, Myer's Corners - Cozine-Bodine-Martling house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 389-391)
    - B-28, 3373 Richmond Terrace, Holland Hook - De Hart house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 392)
    - B-29, Outerbridge Crossing, Richmond Valley - Dissosway house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 393)
    - B-30, Willow Brook Road, Willowbrook - Dongan-Chrisopher house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 394-396)
    - B-31, Tysen's Lane near Hylan Boulevard, New Dorp - Guyon-Lake-Tysen house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 397)
    - B-32, Watchogue and Willow Brook Roads, Graniteville - Pieter Pieterse Hagawout house, later Krusen's and Vreeland's, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 398)
    - B-33, 1424 Richmond Avenue, south of Graniteville - Peter Hagewout (Haughwout) house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 399)
    - B-34, Arthur Kill Road, south of Rossville - Hendrickson(?)-Winants house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 400)
    - B-35, Richmond Road opposite the Moravian Cemetary, New Dorp - Lakeman-Cortelyou-Taylor house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 401)
    - B-36, Watchogue and Willow Brook Roads, Graniteville - John Roll house, later Mersereau's, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 402)
    - B-37, 2329 Richmond Avenue, New Springville - Simonson-Blake house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 403)
    - B-38, 1476 Richmond Road, Dongan Hills - Capt. Thomas Stillwell house, later Britton's and Perine's, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 404-406)
    - B-39, Richmond Avenue, south of New Springville - Barnt Tysen house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 407-408)
    - B-40, 1262 Richmond Terrace, West New Brighton - Cornelius Van Santvoord house, later Krusen's and Pelton's, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 409-411)
  - New York - Rockland County
    - No plate, unidentified, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 412-414)
    - No plate number, B-pg. 215, Middletown Road, Pearl River - Perry-Horne house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 415)
    - No plate number, B-pg. 195, Old Post Road, Spring Valley - Eckerson house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 416-417)
    - B-41, Old King's Highway, Haverstraw - Benjamin Benson house, [1920-1936] (Box 4, Folder 418-420)
    - B-42, Blauvelt - Hendrick Gerritsen Blauvelt house, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 421)
    - B-43, Blauvelt - Johannes Blauvelt house, later Smith's, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 422-423)
    - B-44, road to West Nyack, Blauvelt - Gerret Blauvelt house, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 424-425)
    - B-45, Phillips Hill Road, New City - Blauvelt-Secor house, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 426-427)
    - B-46, Haverstraw Road, New City - Blauvelt-Lane house, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 428-430)
    - B-47, Old Brewery Road, near New City - Blauvelt-Hogencamp house, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 431-432)
    - B-48, Tappan - Daniel De Clark house; De Wint house; Washington's headquarters, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 433-436)
    - B-49, Haverstraw, New City - De Pew house, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 437-440)
    - B-50, Hackensack River, Orangeburg - Peter De Pew house, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 441-443)
    - B-51, south end of Rockland Lake - Haner-Ryder house, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 444-445)
    - B-52, King's Highway, Tappan - Haring house, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 446-448)
    - B-53, road to Tappan, Orangeburg - Abram Lent house, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 449-450)
    - B-54, Orangeburg Road, Nauraushaun, Orangetown - Jeremias Mabie house, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 451-452)
    - B-55, Sickletwon Road, West Nyack - Oblenis house, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 453-454)
    - B-56, Blue Hill Road, Nauraushaun, Orangetown - Isaac Perry house, later Blauvelt's, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 455-456)
    - B-57, Sickletown Road, Nauraushaun, Orangetown - Sickels-Vanderbilt hosue, [1920-1936] (Box 5, Folder 457-458)